<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<metadata>
    <name>Ascended</name>
    <directory>ascended</directory>
    <id>2867038605</id>
    <description>[b]Ascended[/b] is a mod that implies to spice up your gameplay by introducing new stacking difficulty mode, which is heavily inspired by [b1]Eclipse from Risk of Rain 2[/b] and [b]Ascensions from Slay the Spire[/b].

[h1][b]Ascension effects (total of 14 at this moment)[/b][/h1]
[list]
[*] [b]I - Discharged active items[/b]
All newly encountred active items and starting ones as well will be discharged by default.
[*] [b]II - Less room rewards[/b]
25% chance to replace your room award with cloud of nothing
[*] [b]III - Higher shop prices[/b]
All shop items cost 35% more.
[*] [b]IV - Emptier floors[/b]
25% chance to replace any non-vital special room with the empty one
[*] [b]V - Full heart damage since ch. 3[/b]
Speaks for itself
[*] [b]VI - Weaker soul hearts[/b]
Soul hearts will now receive full heart damage. Isn't affected by previous ascension.
[*] [b]VII - Broken destiny[/b]
All characters (except T. Keeper) start with three broken hearts (or 1 in case of regular Keeper)
[*] [b]VIII - Items don't heal you on pickup[/b]
Disables healing for picking up items in any shape of form.
[*] [b]IX - Extra Boss Room each floor[/b]
Every floor will now have additional boss fight just like with the Curse of Labyrinth. Though, beating this extra boss won't award you with an item.
This should work for modded bosses too, but I haven't tested it that much,
[*] [b]X - Room may not gain you charge[/b]
Each third room doesn't charge your active item(s)
[*] [b]XI - Worse beggars and blood donation[/b]
Almost every beggar now has worse payouts.
Blood donation machine though will work just like if you were playing as the Keeper
[*][b]XII - Less room for consumables[/b]
Speaks for itself, but I'd like to note that this one is worked quite well
[*][b]XIII - Less invulnerability[/b]
Isaac will now take damage twice as frequently
[*][b]XIV - Chased by Death[/b]
A Spelunky-styled ghost will now appear on each floor after a certain time threshold.
[/list]

[h1]Additional notes[/h1]
[list]
[*] This mod uses [b]DeadSeaScrolls[/b] as config menu - this means you don't need to install any additional mods. Press [b][C] or [f1][/b] to configure stuff
[*] You can enable freeplay mode in DSS options, which makes progression an optional part.
[*] It's possible to change Ascension number thru `ascend x` console command, where the `x` is a needed ascension. 
[*] Works in multiplayer (both local and through networktest)
[*] Should work fine for most modded characters
[*] This gamemode does its best mostly during Eden streaks
[/list]

[h1]Todo[/h1]
[list]
[*] Up to 20 ascensions
[*] Unlockables
[*] StageAPI compat
[*] Fix A9 issues with minimap and something else
[/list]

[h1]Special thanks[/h1]
[b]Warhamm2000[/b]: Epic Spookster spritesheet and workshop thumbnail
[b]fly_6[/b]: Coding help and playtesting
[b]sodda, Nogisto, ProjectTZ, Danial[/b]: Suggestions &amp; playtesting</description>
    <version>1.1</version>
    <visibility>Public</visibility>
    <tag id="Lua"/>
    <tag id="Hazards"/>
    <tag id="Challenges"/>
    <tag id="Tweaks"/>
</metadata>
